HYPE! Mime Troupe Records UA234
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
HYPE! Mime Troupe Records
1998 -- 2016
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
HYPE! Mime Troupe
UA234
0.55 Linear Feet
17 Digital Object(s)
1 Web sites
37.7 Megabytes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: HYPE! materials; and Web crawls.
Custodial History
Materials donated in July, 2013 by Abby Setterholm, troupe member. Some materials were arranged by semester, but others were undated and arranged by the archivist chronologically as closely as possible.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains clippings, forms, notes, scripts, and web sites concerning the promotional, organizational, and audition materials of HYPE! Mime Troupe.
Biographical / Historical
HYPE! was founded in the fall of 1998 by two Tufts Seniors, Anjali Vashi and Jay Willoughby, as an offshoot of the Cheap Sox improv group. The original troupe also included Ben Connelly and Tracy Erikson.
The troupe's size ranges from five to fourteen members. Members write their own skits, set them to music, and stage their own lighting and title cards. Skits can run from 30 seconds to over 15 minutes for a multi-scene presentation. The troupe hold two major show each academic year. At the end of fall semester they co-host CheapHype with the Cheap Sox, and at the end of spring semester they have a performance. They also perform at Parents' Weekend, at various Tufts Community Days and fund-raising events off-campus. Additionally they stage "guerrilla miming" events were members walk through campus, Davis Square, or Harvard Square and engage with the public. They have also performed at the Oberon Club in Harvard Square.
Although the troupe is funded through the Tufts Community Union, they have no enforced hierarchy within the organization. All decisions are made by unanimous votes.
HYPE! held a special reunion show in the spring 2013 to celebrate the troupe's 15th anniversary. Alumni of HYPE! formed the Broken Box mime troupe in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Student life; Student Activities -- Student Government, Clubs, and Organizations; Student Activities -- Performing Arts
- HYPE! materials, 1998 -- 2013; UA234.001; 0.55 Linear Feet; 17 Digital Object(s); 37.7 Megabytes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials related to the HYPE! Mime Troupe. These materials include productions posters and programs, scripts, photographs, and audition materials, as well as materials regarding the oversight and administration of the organization.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Constitution, 1998; UA234.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1998 -- 2013; UA234.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, Fall, 1998; UA234.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Organization and promational materials, Spring, 1999; UA234.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Organizational materials, Fall, 1999; UA234.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Budgets, 1999 -- 2000; UA234.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Cast list, poster and clipping, Fall, 2000; UA234.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Audition sheets and sign-ups, 2000 -- 2010; UA234.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Posters, 2000 -- 2012; UA234.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Organizational materials and photographs, Spring, 2001; UA234.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Organizational materials, Fall, 2001; UA234.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Publicity clippings, 2001 -- 2008; UA234.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Organizational materials and publicity, Spring, 2002; UA234.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Fall Show, 2003; UA234.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Poster, Fall, 2003; UA234.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Sets and planning, Spring, 2003; UA234.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, Spring, 2004; UA234.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Poster, Spring, 2005; UA234.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Planning and notes, 2005 -- 2011; UA234.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Programs, 2005 -- 2013; UA234.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Organizational materials, 2007 -- 2008; UA234.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Planning notebook, 2008; UA234.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Scripts, Spring, 2009; UA234.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Posters, 2009 -- 2013; UA234.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Organizational materials, 2010; UA234.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Scripts, 2010 -- 2013; UA234.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Audition forms, 2010; UA234.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Scripts, Fall, 2010; UA234.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Musical accompaniment, 2010 -- 2013; UA234.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Digital photographs, 2009; UA234.001.001.00030; 17 Digital Object(s); 37.7 Megabytes
    Physical image CD labeled: Mimez! from Sean.
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe in blue light, 2009-02-28; UA234.000035; 1 Digital Object(s); 7.53 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, 2009-03-28; UA234.000036; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.01 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, arms raised, 2009-03-28; UA234.000037; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.68 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, seated, 2009-03-28; UA234.000038; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.06 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, seated, 2009-03-28; UA234.000039; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.02 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, with surprised expressions, 2009-03-28; UA234.000040; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.4 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, with surprised expressions, 2009-03-28; UA234.000041; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.25 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, 2009-03-28; UA234.000042; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.82 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs on stage, 2009-03-28; UA234.000043; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.64 Megabytes
    - Two HYPE! mimes look into the distance while another looks to the ground, 2009-03-28; UA234.000044; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.48 Megabytes
    - Three HYPE! members mime swinging a golf club, 2009-03-28; UA234.000045; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.69 Megabytes
    - Three HYPE! mimes look into the distance, 2009-03-28; UA234.000046; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.7 Megabytes
    - Two HYPE! mimes with troubled expressions, 2009-03-28; UA234.000047; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.63 Megabytes
    - HYPE! mime on all fours, with lips pursed, looking left, 2009-03-28; UA234.000048; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.08 Megabytes
    - HYPE! mime on all fours, with lips pursed, looking right, 2009-03-28; UA234.000049; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.17 Megabytes
    - Three HYPE! members mime attacking another mime on all fours, 2009-03-28; UA234.000050; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.83 Megabytes
    - HYPE! Mime Troupe performs a scene on stage, 2009-03-28; UA234.000051; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.71 Megabytes
- Web crawls, 2016; UA234.002; 1 Web sites
  Quarterly web crawls of the HYPE Mimez website crawled by DCA, as part of the Student Organizations web collection, to document the presesence of Tufts University student organizations on the web.
  Other Finding Aids
  To see all of websites crawled as part of the Student Organizations web collection, please visit https://archive-it.org/collections/6387
  - HYPE Mimez - Home | Facebook, 2016 April 11; UA234.002.00001; HYPE! Mime Troupe
    General
    Frequency: quarterly crawl. (Inactive)